好滴，下一个应用我们要一起
Okay, so the next app that we're going to build together
编写一个非常简单的天气应用
is a very simple weather application.
我意识到 Windows 10 的 PC 和手机都自带了
Now I realize there are stock apps that come with
很多常用的应用
Windows 10 on the desktop and the phone,
但是这个应用可以让我们表达
however, this one will allow us to express
一点特色和设计感
a little individuality, a little design.
另外我还要演示一些
Also, we'll demonstrate some pretty cool features
在 Windows 10 多平台间非常有趣的特性
of both Windows 10 the platform
以及如何从外部服务中获得
and then how to work with external services
实时的数据，从而让你的应用变得实时
to get data to update and make your apps come alive.
好，首先让我们先运行一下这个 App
So I'll go ahead and run the application.
让我先运行一下它的桌面版
Actually let me run it just on the desktop
但相信我它在手机上
and just have to trust me that it works
也能跑得起来
in the mobile version as well.
这个应用我给它赐名为:
And the name of the application I'm calling
UWP 天气 (●'◡'●)
UWP Weather.
这是一个简单的天气应用
It's a simple weather app.
它会基于当前我在达拉斯的实际位置
It's just going to go out and based on my current location
然后去找出我所处位置的实时天气
here in Dallas, it's going to go out and find the current weather,
像天气情况如何，具体的地理位置在哪
what the weather conditions are, where I'm actually at here.
我现在所处 普莱诺，德克萨斯州。 它还会展示一个
I'm in Plano, Texas and then also will display
在粉色背景下可爱的天气图片
an image, a cute weather image with a hot pink background
图片显示我所在地方的实时天气
to convey what the current weather is where I'm at.
在编写这个 App 中
So in the process of building this, first of all,
这真是一个非常好的开始
this is a great start to a weather application
你编写这个应用并去扩充它，学习
that you can take and extend and you're going
如何去它的功能
to learn how to do that.
你可以添加，比如，使用在线服务
You can add, you know, a two week forecast if you want
提供提前两周的天气预报，具体服务稍后就说
using online services that I'll point you to in this series.
你将要学到一件重要的事情
But one of the main things that you'll learn
是如何利用你 Windows 10 设备上的传感器
is how to use sensors on your device or in actuality
或者定位服务来定位你手机
the location services for Windows 10 to determine
或者电脑的地理位置，
the geo position where the device or your computer
从中获得的经纬度数据
is currently at So that would give the latitude
我们可以用来
and longitude that we can then take
调用外部的天气 Web 服务
and we can make calls out to an external web service
比如 OpenWeatherMap.org 这个网站
like the OpenWeatherMap.org,
它允许我们提交一个地方的经度和维度
which will allow us to give in a place,
然后获得那个地方的天气
a latitude, longitude, will give us the weather
甚至有几小时后、几天后
for that location and even future forecasts
的天气预告
for the hours and days ahead.
从中我们将学习
So it's going to also allow us then
如何从 Web 服务中获取数据
to learn how to retrieve data from a web service
使用一种典型的数据格式化样式
in a typical fashion through a file format
叫做 JSON (JavaScript 对象表述方法)
called JSON (JavaScript Object Notation),
或许你早就熟悉它
maybe you're already familiar with that
知道使用 C# 将它反序列化成
and deserialize that into instances of classes
类实例
that we can work with in C#.
这是一个非常有用的技能，抛开这个例子
Very crucial skill, outside of this example
作为一个开发者，学会它
and throughout the rest of your life
你将终身受益
as a software developer.
你必须知道对于一些数据格式
You have to know how to serialize and desterialize data
像 XML，JSON，如何序列化和反序列化数据
from data formats like XML and JSON
最终实现来回转换
into objects and back.
然后我们还要看看如何使用
And then we're going to look at how to work with
手机模拟器来测试我们的应用
the Phone Emulator to test our application,
不仅仅是测试一些转到手机上运行的部分
not just as it's used on the mobile device itself
像是布局，一些性质
and the layout, things of that nature, but then also
我们还要学会如何去修改位置
how to change the position
例如告诉位置服务
and kind of tell the location services
我们现在在西雅图或者华盛顿
that we're actually coming from, Seattle or Washington, DC,
甚至天朝，等等
or China, or whatever.
我们还要来看一下在使用手机测试时
And so we'll look at a cool feature of the emulator
一项非常酷炫的特性
to do that as well for testing.
之后将为我们的应用创建
And then we're going to take a look at how to build
一个活动磁贴
a Live Tile for our application
我们还将定期地使用地理位置和经纬度
that we'll update periodically with the latest weather
来获取最新的天气
for our geo position, our latitude and longitude.
从中我们不仅学到如何来创建一个活动磁贴
And so that will teach us not only how to build live tiles,
而且包括了如何创建一个 Web 服务
but then also we'll learn how to create a web service
使用ASP.NET MVC 5，从自己的主机来运行这个服务
using ASP.NET MVC 5 and host it out as your website
所以我们集合了相当多有趣的技术来
so we're bring together a lot of cool technologies
构建一个富交互的应用
to build a very interactive application.
下节课，我们将确定布局
So beginning in the next video we'll get started
学习如何去接入一个 Web 服务
with the layout and learning how to access that web service
从中获取我们需要的数据
and get back the data that we need.
那下节课我们正式开始
We'll begin that process in the next video.
到时候见，再见
We'll see you there, thanks.